<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gluten free on (C|B)ook</title>
    <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/tags/gluten-free/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gluten free on (C|B)ook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 13:30:54 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://empijei.science/cooking/tags/gluten-free/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Cake</title>
      <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/chocolate-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 13:30:54 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/chocolate-cake/</guid>
      <description>About this cake and its variants This is one of my favorite recipes:
 The effort is very low and the result is amazing It is gluten free so it can accommodate guests that have trouble with it It can even be made lactose-free if butter is replaced with lactose-free butter or margarine and all the white chocolate is replaced by dark chocolate.  How to melt chocolate and butter Bain-marie Bain-marie is my favorite way to melt chocolate for most recipes as it makes it close to impossible to burn chocolate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chestnut Cake</title>
      <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/chestnut-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 11:59:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/chestnut-cake/</guid>
      <description>How simple can it be? This recipe can be simplified to literally be &amp;ldquo;mix all together; bake&amp;rdquo;.
About the Chestnut paste This is not easy to come by outside of Switzerland but it is a 74% boiled chestnuts 26% sugar mix, so I think this should be fairly easy to make at home (but I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried).
This is how the ingredient I use looks like: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swedish Chocolate Balls</title>
      <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/swedish-chocolate-balls/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 18:46:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/swedish-chocolate-balls/</guid>
      <description>If you want to give your cookies the coffee taste, the water can be replaced completely or partially with the same amount of dark coffee.
This recipe does not require baking nor the usage of knives, therefore is suitable for cooking with kids.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risotto</title>
      <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/risotto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 19:07:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/risotto/</guid>
      <description>Doses are per person, I suggest making it for at least two people.
Flavors Flavors can be composed, like sausage and mushrooms or sausage and saffron, let your fantasy guide you.
 Saffron (use red wine with tannins like salice, primitivo or any non-sweet red wine) Sausage (in this case add the sausage 5 minutes before the end) Squid ink Pumpkin Zucchini and shrimps Cheeses Radicchio  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baci Di Alassio</title>
      <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/baci-di-alassio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 14:51:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/baci-di-alassio/</guid>
      <description>They can be preserved at room temperature for roughly a week. I strongly advise against freezing.
I think they are best after one or two days, not immediately after made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mushroom Paste</title>
      <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/mushroom-paste/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 15:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/mushroom-paste/</guid>
      <description>This paste has a high content of umami, which can be used to enhance and prolong a taste.
It can be easily stored in the freezer in an ice-cube mold for later use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almond cookies</title>
      <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/almond-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 14:31:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/almond-cookies/</guid>
      <description>This is my quick and simplified version of almond bakies (which are like cookies, but are baked instead of cooked).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pesto</title>
      <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/pesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 11:02:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/pesto/</guid>
      <description>Preservation Pesto can be preserved in the fridge for a few days and can be frozen if necessary. I personally use an ice-cube mold so I can have pesto-cubes to unfreeze when needed.
Vegan For a 🌿vegan🌿 alternative to the recipe replace both parmigiano and pecorino with finely ground cashew nuts.
Faster For a faster alternative you can put all ingredients in a food processor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>