<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipes on (C|B)ook</title>
    <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recipes on (C|B)ook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 11:59:17 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chestnut Cake</title>
      <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/chestnut-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 11:59:17 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/chestnut-cake/</guid>
      <description>How simple can it be? This recipe can be simplified to literally be &amp;ldquo;mix all together; bake&amp;rdquo;.
About the Chestnut paste This is not easy to come by outside of Switzerland but it is a 74% boiled chestnuts 26% sugar mix, so I think this should be fairly easy to make at home (but I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried).
This is how the ingredient I use looks like: </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Polpette Al Sugo</title>
      <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/polpette-al-sugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 15:04:45 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/polpette-al-sugo/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swedish Chocolate Balls</title>
      <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/swedish-chocolate-balls/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 18:46:14 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/swedish-chocolate-balls/</guid>
      <description>If you want to give your cookies the coffee taste, the water can be replaced completely or partially with the same amount of dark coffee.
This recipe does not require baking nor the usage of knives, therefore is suitable for cooking with kids.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carbonara</title>
      <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/carbonara/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 12:52:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/carbonara/</guid>
      <description>Cream? No cream? The cream is not in the original recipe but it makes it much easier to obtain a creamy sauce and reduces the risk of scrambling the eggs. I would suggest trying with the cream the first few time you make this and then move on to the traditional version.
Sometimes when I make brioche I end up with some leftover yolk-cream mix and to not throw it away I add it to the whole egg to make a carbonara, it is not the traditional way but I hate to throw away good ingredients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risotto</title>
      <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/risotto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 19:07:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/risotto/</guid>
      <description>Doses are per person, I suggest making it for at least two people.
Flavors Flavors can be composed, like sausage and mushrooms or sausage and saffron, let your fantasy guide you.
 Saffron (use red wine with tannins like salice, primitivo or any non-sweet red wine) Sausage (in this case add the sausage 5 minutes before the end) Squid ink Pumpkin Zucchini and shrimps Cheeses Radicchio  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crema Pasticcera [~Custard]</title>
      <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/crema-pasticcera/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 19:06:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/crema-pasticcera/</guid>
      <description>IMPORTANT NOTE Be careful when you reheat the mix: it will take a while for it to change viscosity, but it will happen very quickly. If you are not quick enough to take it off the heat you might end up with scrambled eggs. If that happens you can still blend the mix but it will not have the right consistency.
Make also sure to constantly whisk, otherwise your custard will burn or make lumps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baci Di Alassio</title>
      <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/baci-di-alassio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 14:51:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/baci-di-alassio/</guid>
      <description>They can be preserved at room temperature for roughly a week. I strongly advise against freezing.
I think they are best after one or two days, not immediately after made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple Pie</title>
      <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/apple-pie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 12:42:48 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/apple-pie/</guid>
      <description>This is one of my all-time favorite cakes, good for all seasons and both for breakfast and dessert.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mushroom Paste</title>
      <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/mushroom-paste/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 15:00:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/mushroom-paste/</guid>
      <description>This paste has a high content of umami, which can be used to enhance and prolong a taste.
It can be easily stored in the freezer in an ice-cube mold for later use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panzanella [alla Norma]</title>
      <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/panzanella/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 14:50:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/panzanella/</guid>
      <description>Panzanella is a good way to put your stale bread to good use: nothing goes to waste!
The two optional ingredients are not from the original recipe, but they are a twist I added.
Keep in mind that ingredients and quantities are just a suggestion: feel free to customize this recipe as much as you like!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Almond cookies</title>
      <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/almond-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 14:31:12 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/almond-cookies/</guid>
      <description>This is my quick and simplified version of almond bakies (which are like cookies, but are baked instead of cooked).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta al pesto</title>
      <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/pasta-al-pesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 11:26:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/pasta-al-pesto/</guid>
      <description>This is my personal version of &amp;ldquo;Pasta al pesto&amp;rdquo;, a recipe from Genova.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pesto</title>
      <link>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/pesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 11:02:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://empijei.science/cooking/recipes/pesto/</guid>
      <description>Preservation Pesto can be preserved in the fridge for a few days and can be frozen if necessary. I personally use an ice-cube mold so I can have pesto-cubes to unfreeze when needed.
Vegan For a 🌿vegan🌿 alternative to the recipe replace both parmigiano and pecorino with finely ground cashew nuts.
Faster For a faster alternative you can put all ingredients in a food processor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>